

ANCA SIMON FULL STACK DEVELOPER C# .NET

(615) 498-2643
ANCARSIMON@GMAIL.COM
https://asimonbio.web.app
https://github.com/ancasimon

ABOUT ME

I love solving technical and business problems and helping users leverage technology to enhance results. My experience as a software developer with an extensive business analysis background gives me the skills to be an effective and successful contributor.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School: Full Stack Developer

Middle Tennessee State University: MA English

Lipscomb University: BA English

PROJECTS @ NSS

GEARUP

Never let the stress of packing prevent you from making great camping and backpacking memories again! GearUp helps you manage your camping gear and quickly create packing lists for new trips in seconds.

It is a single-page React application with CRUD functionality and uses Firebase for database management, authentication, and hosting.

Users can create records to track their gear, and manage the list by filtering by function, weather, and expiration year. They can create trips and quickly put together packing lists for each trip so they can easily prep for their trip when the time comes.

Technologies: Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, Firebase, Github, Google login authentication, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSX, Lucidchart, moment.js, moqups, React, React Router, reactstrap, REST API, Sass, sweetalert2, Webpack

FOODIES UNITE

Wondering what to eat when traveling? This app gives you gourmet meal recommendations for locations around the US and the world. It is a single-page web app with CRUD functionality and uses Firebase for data management, authentication, and hosting. I used Bootstrap for the layout, FontAwesome icons for more visually appealing button icons, and Javascript and jQuery for the program. Users can create boards and add multiple cards to each board with a photo and a title.

Technologies: Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, ESLint, Firebase, Github, Google login authentication, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, JSONLint, Lucidchart, moment.js, moqups, REST API, Sass, Webpack

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2020-2021

A non-profit corporation, providing intensive accelerated software development programs, teaching full-stack software development fundamentals, teamwork, and problem solving. Technologies: Axios, Bootstrap, CSS, ES6 Modules, ESLint, Firebase, Github, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, JSX, Lucidchart, moment.js, moqups, React, React Router, reactstrap, REST API, Sass, sweetalert2, Webpack

- Learned object-oriented programming fundamentals and development best practices, such as single responsibility principle, DRY code, and modularization.
- Built single-page applications using React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and JSON.
- Used Firebase for data management, Google authentication, and deployment, employed Axios method with the Firebase Database REST API, and wrote Promises to call data across multiple data collections. Bundled projects with Webpack, using ESLint for linting.
- Leveraged Bootstrap components for layout and data display. Used FontAwesome for more visually appealing icons. Took advantage of Google Photos to dynamically upload photos in apps.
- Used Github for project planning and version control, mapped out relationships between different data collections in entity relationship diagrams (ERDs) via Lucidchart, and built wireframes for new projects using moqups.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS ANALYST

TEKsystems | 2016

An information technology and services recruiting organization, working to bring the appropriate expertise and talent to provide solutions for their clients.

- Modernized computer applications at the TN Department of Human Services in order to help DHS users be more effective in their roles
- Wrote and managed business requirements and technical specifications
- Managed project commitments and metrics
- Acted as the Scrum Master for the development team

BUSINESS ANALYST & PRODUCT MANAGER UL Workplace Health & Safety | 2011-2016

A business unit of Underwriters Laboratories, providing software programs and e-learning training to help improve the safety of workers across diverse industries.

- Worked with customers, support, sales, marketing, solutions consultants, and the management team to define the product roadmap
- Managed the end-to-end Product Management process that spans market needs identification to product development to product launch and support
- Planned release schedule, deliverables, goals, and milestones
- Defined requirements
- Collaborated with the development, QA, documentation, and engineering teams to ensure product roadmap items were implemented successfully
- Designed and maintained project documentation
- Provided support to Sales (helping with RFPs, participating on customer and prospect calls, conducting demos, and providing roadmap information)

TECHNICAL WRITER

Epic Systems Corporation | 2005-2010

Healthcare software provider, offering a centralized site for a patient's information.

- Wrote and reviewed a wide variety of technical documents: development release notes, user guides, online help, quick start guides, training companions, design specifications, and test scripts
- Contributed to developing a new strategy for enhanced reporting documentation tools
- Contributed to a major revamp of the online help system
- Led customer training sessions on using documentation deliverables and documentation management tools
- Provided onsite go-live assistance and conducted user training sessions